A Guide to the Papers of Collins Denny, 1886-1958 and n. d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Collins Denny 1886-1958 and n. d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
2672-i
This collection consists of 500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
Collection contains journals, 1880 & 1886-87 of Denny's trips to Europe & around the world, correspondence, 1886-87 regarding the trip & correspondence, 1939-40 regarding Denny's refusal to become a bishop in the United Methodist Church, reports, clippings, photographs, scrapbook, 1931 from his 50th wedding anniversary, personal notebook, 1893-1910 and Denny family Bible records.
Contents List
- 6 letters from Bishops McTyerie, Hendrix, and W. R. Denny re: Trip around the world. 1886
- 8 letters of introduction for Collins Denny. ca. 1886
- 7 invitations to Collins Denny while on his trip around the world. ca. 1886-1887
- 6 letters of Recommendation for Collins Denny to Chancelor Garland. 1890
- 6 membership cards, N. S. D. A. R., of various members of the Denny family. 1895-1932
- Newspaper clippings and typescript re: Collins Denny's aid in World War I. ca. 1923
- AMSs, "A Joint Statement By Five Bishops" signed by Collins Denny, U. V. W. Darlington, et al ca. 1924, 11 pp.
- 19 letters to and from various church officials re: Unification and publication of articles on Unification. 1936-1937
- 20 letters to and from officials in Methodist Church and Unification Conference. 1939 May-Sept.
- AM, with mimeographed and printed copies: Collins Denny's letter to the Methodist Unification Conference. 1939 April
- 28 letters and telegrams to and from the Unification Conference re: refusal to become a Bishop. 1939 Jan.-May
- 15 letters to and from the General Conference re: refusal to become a Bishop. 1940 April June
- 3 TL copies, Collins Denny, Jr. to various Methodist Church officials concerning his father. 1943 May 20, July 23, Aug. 10
- TL (carbon copy), [Collins Denny, Jr.] to R. H. Woody re: disposition of papers of Collins Denny. 1947 July 8
- AMS, "Provisional Plan of Organization for purpose of pertuating the Methodist Episcopal Church...in South Caroline..." n. d.
- AMSs, "Minority Report of the Committee on the Status of the Negro" by Collins Denny and H. H. White. n. d.
- AM, Floor plan of a house n. d., 2 pp.
- Journal of a trip through Europe by Collins Denny 1880 July-Oct., 1 vol. 231 pp.
- Vol. I of a Journal of a trip around the world by Collins Denny 1886-1887, 276 pp.
- Vol. II of a Journal of a trip around the world by Collins Denny 1886-1887, 223 pp.
- Photograph of Collins Denny, William H. Baker, J. Montgomery MacFarland, William J. Manning, and William H. Whittlesey. 1872 Dec. 25
- Docket of Collins Denny 1877, 6 pp.
- Cash Book of Collins Denny 1877 Sept., 20 pp.
- 3 Account Books of Collins Denny. ca. 1881-1886
- Diary of [W. R. Denny] containing genealogical notes and accounts of a trip to Europe. ca. 1893-1910
- "Catalogue of the Vanderbilt Chapter, Phi Beta Kappa", 85 pp., with notice of Collins Denny, p. 66. 1914, 1 vol.
- Scrapbook of Wedding Anniversary cards ca. 1931, ca. 30 pp.
- Biographical sketch of Oswald Thomas Denny, 1849-1927 1949, 1 pamphlet, 30 pp.
- "The First Hundred Years of Braddock St. Methodist Church." (Home church of Collins Denny in his youth.) 1958, 1 vol.
- 2 photocopies of Denny Bible records.